Guide to the John Miller Papers on the Homeport Movement TAM.349
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
John Miller Papers on the Homeport Movement
1981-1993
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Miller, John
TAM.349
9 Linear Feet in 9 record cartons
The John Miller Papers on the Homeport Movement (dated 1981-1993) contain clippings, reports, correspondence, ephemera, and organizing materials related to John Miller's work with grassroots organizations opposing the U.S. Navy's Strategic Homeport Plan. John Miller is an organizer and activist who worked with several organizations opposing homeporting, including Mobilization for Survival (MSF), the Coalition for a Nuclear-Free Harbor (CNFH), and the North Atlantic Network (NAN).
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by John M. Miller in 2006. The accession number associated with this gift is 2006.025.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Biographical Note
John Miller (born 1955) is a New York-based organizer and activist who worked with several organizations opposing the construction of strategic homeports around the United States in the 1980s and 1990s. Miller was an organizer in Mobilization for Survival (MFS), the Coalition for a Nuclear-Free Harbor (CNFH), and the North Atlantic Network (NAN). He was the coordinator for CNFH's Task Force on Nuclear Weapons Accidents, and served as editor for Mobilization for Survival's quarterly newsletter, The Mobilizer. He also contributed to the National Campaign on Strategic Homeporting. This campaign was formed at a 1987 meeting in Washington, D.C. by representatives from grassroots coalitions working to stop homeporting across the United States. The campaign and its affiliated groups lobbies against the construction of new naval homeports citing public health and safety concerns related to the housing of nuclear-capable naval vessels near major U.S. cities.
Related Materials
Mobilization for Survival Records (TAM 127)
Scope and Contents
The John Miller Papers on the Homeport Movement (dated 1981-1993) contain organizing materials and clippings related to John Miller's work with grassroots organizations opposing the U.S. Navy's Strategic Homeport Plan in the late 1980s. Miller worked with several organizations involved in the anti-homeport movement including Mobilization for Survival, the Coalition for a Nuclear-Free Harbor, the North Atlantic Network, and the National Campaign on Strategic Homeporting. Materials related to his involvement with all of these groups are included among his papers, and consist of correspondence, pamphlets, reports, and conference organizing materials related to efforts to raise opposition to the construction of naval ports. A large portion of these materials relate specifically to the Coalition for a Nuclear-Free Harbor's efforts to resist the construction of a naval base in Staten Island. They also include two boxes of clippings related to both national and local homeporting campaigns.
Staten Island (New York, N.Y.); Port districts -- New York (State) -- New York.; Antinuclear movement -- New York (State) -- New York.; Antinuclear movement -- United States.; Environmentalists -- New York (State) -- New York.; Hazardous wastes -- Environmental aspects.; Nuclear disarmament.; Mobilization for Survival (Organization); Coalition for a Nuclear-Free Harbor (New York, N.Y.)
- Homeport Reports and Research, 1981-1996 (Box 1)
- Local Homeporting Campaigns, 1986-1997 (Box 2)
- North Atlantic Network Conferences, 1986-1991 (Box 3)
- Philippines Nuclear Power: Clippings and Reports, 1983-1986 (Box 3)
- North Atlantic Network: Correspondence, Lobbying, Newsletters, and Conference Organizing, 1986-1988 (Box 4)
- Coalition for a Nuclear-Free Harbor: Correspondence and Research, 1985-1988 (Box 4)
- North Atlantic Network: Conferences and Lobbying, 1986-1987 (Box 5)
- Coalition for a Nuclear-Free Harbor: Staten Island and New York Harbor Campaign, 1983-1990 (Box 5, Box 6, Box 7)
- Base Closures: Reports, 1988-1993 (Box 7)
- Homeport Clippings, 1984-1993 (Box 8, Box 9)